Guide to the Maurice Shapiro Environmental Health Collection, 1919-2001 UA.90.F65
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Public Health, 1948-2001; III.
  - Conferences and Meetings, 1949-1997; 3.
    - Tri-State Environmental Symposium, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - United States-Taiwan Conference on Pollution Control Technology, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Western Electric Industry-Education Seminar, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - White House Conference on Climate Change, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - World Health Assembly, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - General, 1948-2001; 4.
    - Alcoa, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Allegheny County Department of Works- Bureau of Utility Systems, 1965-1976 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Allegheny County Emergency Operation Plan, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Allegheny County Public Health Bulletin, 1962-1980 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Allegheny County Sanitary Authority, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Appalachian Mineral Resource Development, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Appalachian Regional Commission., 1963-1975 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Ashland oil spill, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Board of Environmental Health: Rent Withholding, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Bureau of Environmental Health Services, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Chambers Development Co., 1990 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Community Health, Inc., 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Community Health, Inc., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Community studies, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Descriptive material, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Dust fall, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Engineering News-Record, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Environmental Control Technicians, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Environmental Health Personnel Review, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Environmental Health Services Task Force Notebook, 1966-1971 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Environmental health training, 1969-1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Environmental sanitation, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Field structure of PHS Environmental Health Programs, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Fluoridation, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "A Garbageer's Dream", undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Region Construction Aggregates, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Region Land and Water Studies for Environmental Analysis, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Health Concerns in Chemical Emergencies, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Health and Environment Subcommittee Materials, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Health Science and China, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Housing, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Human Identity in Megalopolis, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Land Use Policy in Pennsylvania, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Maps and articles on environmental problems, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1979-1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-1995 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Mutagens, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - National Alliance for Energy Contingency Planning for Health Resources, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - National Center for Resources for Recovery Monthly, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - National Council for International Health, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - National Science Foundation, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Newsletters and brochures, 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Papers, 1960-1992 (Box 8, Folder 33-34)
    - Papers, 1960-1992 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Pennsylvania Department of Health, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Pennsylvania Health Council, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania Environmental Protection Agency Agreement, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Pennsylvania Environmental Quality Board, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Pennsylvania forestry materials, 1976-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Pennsylvania's Health, 1970-1977 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Pennsylvania's Master Environmental Plan, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Pesticides, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Pittsburgh Taxicab Study, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Pollution, 1961-1979 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Pond, M. Allen, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Preparing Public Health Leaders for the 1990s, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Regional Development Plan, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Reports, 1966-1994 (Box 9, Folder 17-19)
    - Role of Education and Research, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Sanitarians, 1948-1970 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Schreiber, Helmut, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Supply of Health Manpower, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Surfactants, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "A System for Prevention, Assessment and Control of Exposures and Health Effects from Hazardous Sites", 1984 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Terrorism, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Toxic Substances Control Act, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Training Program for Health Services Administration and Planning, undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - "Upgrading by Biological Process Modifications and Additions", 1972 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Urban Comparative Risk Program, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Westinghouse, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Weyerhaeuser, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Illness and Disease, 1952-1995; 5.
    - Asbestos, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Breast cancer, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Cancer, 1980-1984 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Cardiovascular disease, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Center for Environmental Epidemiology, 1979-1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Communicable Disease Control, 1962-1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Detection of Airborne Mutagenic and Carcinogenic Compounds, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Disease transmission, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - E. coli, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Electromagnetic fields, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Epidemiological Studies of Risks Associated with the Agricultural Use of Sewage Sludge, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Feasibility Study to Resolve Questions on the Relationship of Arsenic in Skin Cancer to Drinking Water, 1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Health Maintenance and Promotion, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Legionella, 1964-1967 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Legionella, 1967-1985 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Lung disease, 1963-1982 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Occupational medicine, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Pittsburgh area materials, 1960-1977 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Pollution: Its Impact on Mental Health, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Promoting Health, Preventing Disease, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Radioactive gold, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Radon, 1985-1991 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Report on the Findings of the Brighton Heights Childhood Morbidity Survey, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - A Report of the Meeting of the Association of Schools of Public Health at the Center for Disease Control, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Reproductive Hazards in Coke Oven Workers, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - The Role of Free Living Amoebae Occurring in Heated Effluents as Causative Agents of Human Disease, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Salmonella, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Sewickley epidemic, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Task Force on Environmental Cancer and Heart and Lung Disease, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Trace Elements in Human Tissue, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Viruses, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Workshop on Health Promotion/Disease Prevention, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - X-radiation, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Occupational Health, 1969-1992; 6.
    - Delivery of Occupation Health Services, undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Disciplines of Occupational and Environmental Medicine note, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Drake Chemical Worker's Health Registry, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Final Proposal and Recommendations for the Implementation of an Injury Surveillance Program in Allegheny County, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Health Surveillance Programs for Populations at Work, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Injury prevention, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Injury prevention, 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Long-Term Mortality Study of Steelworkers, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Occupational Infections, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Occupational Safety and Health Administration, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Recognition and Control of Occupational Diseases, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Reports, 1980-1991 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - A View of Occupational Health Manpower, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Worksite Health Promotion and Program Evaluation, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Research Files, 1919-2000; IV.
  The Research Files Series contains material on research topics that Shapiro was interested in. For the majority of these files, Shapiro kept a numbered and organized list that broke down his interests by topic. These areas of interests became the subseries reflected in this arrangement. There are 12 subseries: Air; Animal Vector Diseases; Energy; Environmental Hygiene; Food Sanitation; General; Lead; Public Health Administration; Sanitation; Sewage; Waste; and Water. Each subseries is arranged first by the numbered system that Shapiro had assigned in his own office, then is arranged alphabetically by accompanying related material that he had not assigned a number to. The material in this series dates from 1919 to 2000, and includes reports, publications, correspondence, research data, and notes.
  - Air, 1940-1997; 1.
    - Air Engineering Newsletter, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Air Pollution in Allegheny County, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Air Pollution: The Role and Limits of Consent, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Air Quality and Meteorology, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Air Quality Permitting Criteria including Best Available Technology for Hospital/Infectious Waste Incineration Facilities, 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Air Resources Planning and Engineering, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Air Toxics Policy and Procedures for New Source Review, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1972-1980 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Pollution Control Advisory Committee, 1994-1997 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Quality, 1972-1986 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Quality, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Quality, 1988-1990 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Quality, 1990-1992 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Quality, 1993-1994 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Air Quality, 1995-1997 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Article XIII, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Article XVII, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Article XX, 1981-1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Article XX, 1987-1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Article XXI, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Recommended Criteria for Suspended Particulate Matter, Sulfur Dioxide and Settled Particulates in Allegheny County, Pennsylvania, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Regulation Subcommittee Minutes, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Regulation Subcommittee Minutes, 1991-1994 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Rules and Regulations, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Rules and Regulations, 1969-1972 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Smoke Control in Pittsburgh, 1950-1968 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Allegheny County Health Department- Smoke Control in Pittsburgh, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Amendments to Allegheny County's Portion of the Pennsylvania State Implementation Plan for the Attainment and Maintenance of the National Ambient Air Quality Standards, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Auto Emissions, 1965-1967 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Brochures, 1962-1976 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Bulletins, 1965-1993 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Bureau of Air Pollution Control, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 19-20)
    - Clean air, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Clean Air Monitor, 1965-1977 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Coke oven emissions, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Conference papers, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - ECAO Working Review Session, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Education, 1969-1976 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Environmental Protection Agency, 1979-1981 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Evolution of Federal Air Pollution Control Policy, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP), 1981 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Health Costs of Air Pollution, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Indoor Air Quality, 1940-1981 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Indoor Air Quality, 1980-1985 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Indoor Air Quality, 1986-1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Indoor Air Quality, 1985-1993 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Indoor Air Quality Symposium, 1978-1989 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Journal of the Air Pollution Control Association, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Journal articles, 1974-1978 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kosmos Emission Control Plan, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Legislation and regulations, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Manpower figures, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Manuals, 1986-1987 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Minutes of Conference on the Epidemiology of Air Pollution, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Motor Vehicle Pollution Control Board Bulletin, 1965-1967 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - National Conference on Air Pollution, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
    - Newsclips, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Newsletters, 1981-1989 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Odor, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - PAH Content of Exhaust Gases from Fuels with Different Aromatic Fractions, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Papers and publications, 1954-1965 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Papers and publications, 1971-1978 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Papers and publications, 1980-1991 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Particulate table, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Pennsylvania's Implementation Plan, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Pollution, 1966-1979 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Pollution, 1979-1982 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Pure Air for PA, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Recommendations and Summary of Federal Abatement Conference on Interstate Air Pollution, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Report on Stationary Stacks, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Ship Air Emissions, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Smog pollution, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Steel, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - A Study of Acute Health Effects of Air Pollution in Allegheny County, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 32-33)
    - Study Indicates Sulfates Account for at Least 187,000 Deaths per Year, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Summary list of research projects on air pollution, 1958 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Surveys, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Testimony of the Ad Hoc Emergency Committee for Clean Air, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Workshop on Indoor Air Quality Research Needs, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Animal Vector Diseases, 1919-1976; 2.
    - 5100- Mosquitoes, 1956-1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - 5101- Identification of mosquitoes, 1936-1957 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - 5102- Mosquito control, 1949-1961 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - 5105- Fishes in relation to mosquito control in ponds, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - 5106- Anopheles mosquitoes in Yugoslavia and their zoophilism, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 5108- Alameda County mosquito abatement district, 1950-1958 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - 5109- Mosquito control- Importance of plant types on impounded waters, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 5110- California Mosquito Control Association, 1947-1954 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - 5111- Vector control, 1952-1959 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - 5200- Flies, 1962-1969 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - 5201- Control of flies, 1949-1959 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - 5201.1- Host contaminant, 1959-1964 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - 5300- Insects, 1950-1962 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - 5301- Ectoparasites, 1950-1959 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - 5302- Insect control, DDT, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - 5304- Insecticides, 1966 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - 5305- Arthropod-borne diseases, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - 5305.1- Arthropod control, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - 5306- Cockroaches, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - 5307- Lice, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - 5400- Rodents, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - 5401- Rodent control, 1959-1976 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - 5402- Rodenticides, 1948-1965 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - 5403- Diseases from rats, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Energy, 1954-1985; 3.
    - Analysis of Particulate Matter Collected from the #4 Battery Coke Oven Stack by Computer Controlled Scanning Electron Microscopy, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Appalachian Mineral Resource Development: Environmental Factors, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Coal, 1975-1980 (Box 14, Folder 31-32)
    - Coal gasification, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 33-36)
    - Coal miner's pneumoconiosis, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Comparative Costs and Performances for Recently Developed Conventional Underground Storage Fields, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Department of Energy activities, undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Development Document for Effluent Limitations Guidelines and New Source Performance Standards for the Petroleum Refining Point Source Category, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Development Document for Interim Final Effluent Limitations Guidelines and Proposed New Source Performance Standards for the Oil and Gas Extraction Point Source Category, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Effects of Land Disposal of Secondary Effluent on the Accumulation of Trace Elements in Terrestrial Ecosystems, undated (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Energy in the Development Strategy of the Sahel, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Energy Research and Development Administration, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Environmental Aspects of Fuel Conversion Technology, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Environmental Features at Cheswick Power Station, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Environmental Impacts of Coal Mining and Processing, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - An Experimental Approach to the Determination of Pulmonary Carcinogenic Influences of Shale Oil Effluents, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Flue gas, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Health Aspects of Fossil-Fuel Electric Power Plants, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Health Implications of Western Coal Development, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Impact of Regulations on Coal Conversion Plants, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Joint Conference on Technology and Governance in Achieving Environmental Quality, 1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Joint Power Generation Conference, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Land use, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Life on Power Alley, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Man and Resources, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Nuclear materials, 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Oak Ridge National Laboratory, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Our Side of the Story, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - The Outlook for Gas Conservation, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Pennsylvania Master Siting Study, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Pennsylvania Refining Industry Reports, 1964-1977 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - A Post Licensing Study of Community Effects at Two Operating Nuclear Power Plants, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Potential Health Impacts of Coal Conversion Technology, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Predicting Socioeconomic Impacts of Energy Development, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Preliminary Evaluation of Perc-Coal Conversion Solid and Hazardous Wastes, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Report of the Committee on Health and Environmental Effects of Increased Coal Utilization, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Research Needs Related to Air Pollution from the Coal Conversion Process, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Resolution of Conflicts between Underground Extraction of Coal Resources and Dedication and Management of Areas as National Parks and Nature Reserves, 1980-1981 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Resource Recovery Update, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Resources, 1961-1971 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Selected Impacts of Electric Utility, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Solid Waste Management of Coal Conversion Residuals from a Commercial-Size Facility, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 28-29)
    - Solubility and Toxicity of Potential Pollutants in Solid Coal Waste, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - State Taxation Policies, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Synthoil Process, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Three New Organizations on the Pittsburgh Energy Scene, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Total Energy Management for Hospitals, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Treatment and Disposal of Atomic Energy Industry Wastes, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Water problems associated with coal conversion, 1977 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Where Have the Farmlands Gone?, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Environmental Hygiene, 1939-1971; 4.
    - 4000- General, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - 4000.1- American Academy of Environmental Engineers, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - 4001- Waste and recycling, undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - 4100- Garbage collection and disposal, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - 4101- Bibliography, 1950-1954 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - 4101- Bibliography, 1955-1961 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - 4102- Garbage disposal, 1949-1964 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - 4103- Dempster-Dumpster system, 1947-1951 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - 4104- Incinerators, 1949-1955 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - 4105- Sanitary landfill, 1950-1952 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - 4105- Sanitary landfill, 1952-1969 (Box 15, Folder 48)
    - 4106- Composting, 1950-1955 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - 4106- Composting, 1955-1956 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - 4106- Composting, 1956-1971 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - 4107- Garbage grinders, 1952-1955 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 4108- Solid waste disposal, 1967-1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - 4200- Housing- General, 1939-1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - 4201- City planning, 1948-1961 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - 4202- Laws and codes, 1952-1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - 4204- Water supply, 1949-1954 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - 4205- Illumination, 1951-1954 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - 4206- Population movements and housing trends, 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - 4207- Garbage grinders, 1947-1954 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - 4208- Progress, City of San Francisco, 1947-1948 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - 4209- Planning, other communities, 1948-1959 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - 4211- Fringe area sanitation, 1960 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - 4212- Yonkers housing evaluation survey, 1951 (Box 16, Folder 14)